dotzot.in 2016-04-17

# Privacy Policy of Dotzot

DTDC E-COMMERCE LOGISTICS LIMITED (“DELL”) understands the importance of protecting the privacy of users of the DotZot website www.dotzot.in. The information collected on the Dotzot website is used to market and improve the services of DELL and its subsidiaries’, to improve the content and services on the DotZot web site and make it easier to use and more appropriate to individual users and to contact its users with updates to the web site or for other marketing purposes. DELL may use this information, with the users’ permission, for the above purposes.

DELL never shares any information obtained on or from the DotZot website with any other organization, and will not do so in future, unless required by law. DELL will not sell information obtained through the DotZot website to any party or parties.

Certain areas of the DotZot website, including but not limited to the sections on ‘Tracking’, ‘Service Guide’, ‘Franchisee’, ‘Corporate Solutions’, ‘Careers’ and ‘eSolutions’ require registration or a password for access. Information obtained from registered users of these areas may also be used for DELL’s marketing purposes, and cookies may be used in those and other areas, as is described in this privacy policy. Information obtained in these areas may also be used in accordance with agreements governing access to and use of the specific areas, including, but not necessarily limited to the ‘Tracking’ section on the DotZot website. In addition, visitors to the DotZot website may choose to register for a DotZot website username and password to simplify access to some interactive features on the DotZot website. Log file data and other information gathered from registered users of the DotZot website are used to improve the customer experience of the users of the DotZot website.

The DotZot website login currently provides users with access to Tracking, Location Finder, Price and Time Finder, Create Shipment and Request Pickup. In the future, DELL may add other features to those accessed through the DotZot website Login.

Please also see the DELL's ‘Conditions of Carriage’ for terms of carriage, limitations of liability, and disclaimers of warranty and general terms applicable to all delivery services and various information used and provided with the services of DELL.

Certain shipment data will be provided to the authorities of the country of transit or destination for customs and tax clearance or for security screening, as required by the laws of such country. The information provided would usually include: shipper name and address, receiver name and address, description of the goods, number of pieces, weight and value of shipment.

For more information on this Privacy Policy, please refer to the detailed section on the privacy policy below.

1\. Information collected about visitors to the DotZot web site:  
The DELL web server uses an extended log file format which captures: date and time of visit, referring address (location from which a visitor comes to the DotZot website), type of Internet browser, and visitor's IP address. 

2\. Personal Information collected on the DotZot website:  
Several areas of the DotZot website ask for personal information. They include the username registration, features of managing the user account of the users and registration pages for various online services offered by DELL on the DotZot website. This list may be expanded without notice. In the event that it is expanded, additional information may be required. In these areas, the user’s name, address, email address, billing information, and business profile are requested. This information is collected to help us further develop DELL’s services, to provide users access to various DELL’s internet-based information and product services, and to bill users for those services if users elect to use them. 

3\. Manner of use of the user information collected on the DotZot website  
The information collected through the DotZot website site helps DELL identify the type of web site content the customers value most. DELL uses this information to market and improve the DotZot website and its services. DELL also use this information to send you email notifications about updates to the DotZot website, and to contact the users by other means for marketing and other purposes. DELL’s policy is to not give, sell or otherwise distribute the information collected through this site to third parties outside of DELL and its subsidiaries (unless required by law); provided, however, in some cases DELL may use suppliers to assist DELL in collecting, using or otherwise processing for DELL’s benefit the information obtained through the DotZot website. DELL’s practice requires its suppliers to conduct such activities consistent with this policy and DELL’s requirements of maintaining privacy of DELL’s customers. 

4\. Use of third party links on the DTDC website  
Parts of the DotZot website consist of products and services hosted by subsidiaries and third-party businesses. When users leave the DotZot website to visit one of these sites, the only information transferred to the third-party is the fact that the user came from the DotZot website.

This practice allows the third-party to monitor their web site traffic, but does not provide them with any information about the users of the DotZot website. DELL is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of third-party sites. Users are advised to consult the privacy policies at those third party websites to determine how the user’s information may be used.

5\. Cookies, their functionality on the DTDC website, how to remove them from the user’s hard drive:  
A cookie is a series of data characters that, when programmed into a web site, is placed by the web server into the browser's application folder on the user’s computer. Once placed onto the user’s computer, the cookie will allow the web site to "recognize" you as a unique user of the website. 

Cookies help DELL with the capability to personalize information for certain segments of its customer base. They are also are used to allow DELL the opportunity to associate individual customers with their information profiles. For example, through the use of cookies, the DotZot website username can "remember and auto fill" your user ID when users login their DotZot website Login username on the DotZot website from their computer.

Cookies can be removed from a user’s hard drive. Also, depending on what type of web browser and what browser version the user of the DotZot website is using, users may be able to change the properties on their cookie file so that cookies are not used or saved. Please check with the browser provider for more information on removing cookies.

Contact Details:  
The registered office of DELL is:  
DTDC E-COMMERCE LOGISTICS LTD,   
2nd Floor, No.2, Victoria Road,   
Bengaluru - 560047. Karnataka  
Users can also write to DELL for support at its email address: feedback@dotzot.in  
DELL reserves the right to amend the Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice. Please check back frequently in the event of changes. The use of the DotZot website constitutes a user’s agreement to this Privacy Policy.
